We Were Warned.
2012 is a action, adventure, science fiction film directed by Roland Emmerich.
Adrian Helmsley, part of a worldwide geophysical team investigating the effect on the earth of
radiation from unprecedented solar storms, learns that the earth's core is heating up.
He warns U.S.
President Thomas Wilson that the crust of the earth is becoming unstable and that without proper
preparations for saving a fraction of the world's population, the entire race is doomed.
Meanwhile, writer Jackson Curtis stumbles on the same information.
While the world's leaders race to build "arks" to escape the impending
cataclysm, Curtis struggles to find a way to save his family.
Meanwhile, volcanic eruptions and earthquakes of
unprecedented strength wreak havoc around the world.
Jackson Curtis, played by John Cusack.
Kate Curtis, played by Amanda Peet.
Adrian Helmsley, played by Chiwetel Ejiofor.
Laura Wilson, played by Thandiwe Newton.
Carl Anheuser, played by Oliver Platt.
Gordon Silberman, played by Tom McCarthy.
2012 is a 2009 American epic apocalyptic disaster film directed by Roland Emmerich, written by Emmerich and Harald Kloser, and
starring John Cusack, Chiwetel Ejiofor, Amanda Peet, Oliver Platt, Thandiwe Newton, Danny Glover, and Woody Harrelson.
Based on the 2012 phenomenon, its plot follows numerous characters, including novelist Jackson Curtis (Cusack) and geologist Adrian Helmsley (Ejiofor), as
they struggle to survive an eschatological sequence of events including earthquakes, volcanic eruptions, megatsunamis, and a global flood.
Filming, initially planned to take place in Los Angeles, began in
Vancouver in August 2008 and wrapped two months later.
An extensive marketing campaign was launched for the film, which included the creation of a website from its main characters' point of view
and a viral marketing website on which filmgoers could register for a lottery number to save them from the ensuing disaster.
Released in the United States by Sony Pictures Releasing on November 13, 2009, 2012 received mixed reviews, but was a commercial success,
grossing $791.2 million worldwide against a production budget of $200 million, becoming the fifth highest-grossing film of 2009.
The film was nominated for Best Action, Adventure, or Thriller Film and Best Special Effects at the
36th Saturn Awards, and for Best Visual Effects at the 15th Critics' Choice Awards.
The film explores themes of race against time, maya
civilization, civilization, natural disaster, earthquake.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.